one of our friends would you like to
test windows 11
since it has just been released and yes
you don't have a spare machine like me
don't worry i'm going to show you how to
run a fully functional windows 11
on a virtual machine on linux using qemu
and kvm yes so the reason why i'm
showing this
is because i went to the internet and i
checked on youtube
and google and everybody is talking
about windows 11 but nobody
shows how to run it on a virtual machine
so i thought i might
well as do it and make a video about it
and so the guy
you guys can play and test it like me so
the first things we need
uh build of windows 11 that is two one
nine nine six
and the second thing is what i owe
intent okay to get what i owe intent
we need to go to this link i'll put a
link at description i put a link in the
description and once you land here
the safest bet is just to go to the
latest word io
and why we are using this because we are
going if you go to archive
then you can see from 2015
till 2021 we have we have released the
drivers forward io
this will be used for qemu kvm so if you
click on the link
we have to download this iso the word
iowin019190
which is the latest one it's 497 max in
size
just download it i have already
downloaded previously so these are the
only two files that you require all
right and i assume you have a functional
qamu installation on your linux box all
right
so to start off we have to fire up a
word manager
virtual virtual machine manager that is
qmu virtual
machine manager and it will load up and
as you can see i already have a mac os
vm if you don't know i am running bixer
on this machine too
i'll put a link in the description so
you can see how i did it all right
right now i'm going to install windows
11 so click on new
file new virtual machine and once this
loads up we need to
look select local install media and
find the iso so choose iso or cd-rom
click on browse and once if this open
click on browse local
i wish i can speak today and select the
windows iso that you have downloaded
all right so it automatically detects
windows 10 don't worry guys it's
windows 11 i mean i don't know why it
detects windows windows 10
that is qmu still detects it as windows
and click on forward
memory i don't have much memory so i can
allocate it for gigs
safely you can allocate more if you want
and cpu can allocate more
and storage is see 40 i just have 31.7
gigs left
on this linux partition so i
cannot give that much i will have to
even go lesser than 40 so
on the safe side i will go 25 don't
scream at me
if you have space give hundred i mean if
i had space i would give 100
gb but i don't have space on this day so
i'm going to be safe side with 25
uh i would select hundreds so select 100
if you guys have space but right now i
don't have space so i'm going to select
and i just allocated two cores of my cpu
because i have only four cores so if you
have like 16 cores allocate it
all right so click on forward and this
is the final step
so we need to rename it windows 11
and windows 11 and qmu that is how i
rename it
so choose your name and storage you see
this is a dynamic storage
it will not allocate 25 gigs all at once
um
that's good and please remember to
select customize configuration before
and install because we need to do some
customization network selection looks
fine
click on finish once we click on finish
this is the screen that loads up and i'm
going to walk you through
each of these one by one not each of
these but most majority of these
and yes i forgot before we need to do
before we need to check on the
preferences and make sure you have
enabled xml editing checked on your
virtual
world manager all right so let me close
that
because we'll be modifying xml with our
hand so all right
all right so this looks good okay so
coming down
we have firmware you can we you see we
have bias
if you want a bias formula that's okay
but i am going to change the firmware to
uefi the newer ones and each time you
make a change please remember to click
on apply
all right so i've applied it looks good
nothing to change here os information
looks fine
okay cpus yes this is the place this is
why we enabled xml editing okay
so you see i have four cpu scores i'm
allocating two
you want if you can't want you can
change the topology this is probably for
a later video not
the beginner one like this so click on
the xml and this is what we need to
change
come down here and select this clock
offset local time select these two lines
and hit on delete
and then come to this part where it says
edge pet
please present yes just say yes and not
no click on apply and why we did this
because it will improve
our cpu performance in a virtual machine
memory you can change
it i'm going to keep it at four gigs all
right suits
words choose whatever suits you sata
disk okay now the virtual disk bus
that is sata we are going to change it
to what i o that is why we
downloaded the word i o drivers from
fedora people because what io has a
better performance than stata all right
that is why i mean i'm gonna give you a
very functional machine with the minimum
resources
okay click on apply sata cd rom is the
windows 11
nic card okay again device model this is
network source is fine again change it
to what i o
why asking me because again it will give
you better network performance i'm going
to prove it to you just
okay so okay otherwise than that if your
video q qxl
qxl is fine if you you can also select
word i o
it gives you a little bit of 3d
acceleration i don't know if
i'm going to get it because i have my
legacy machine
machine so i'm going to keep it to qxl
uh
next storage okay that's all i think
we need to add one more hardware which
is
uh a cd or cd-rom
so select on cd-rom device and select
click on manage bus type there's no vert
ios we'll keep at that sata
click on manage and what you know what
we are going to select
the uh the word io iso that we had
downloaded remember what i o win iso you
will see the use of this with this
will install the network drivers and the
disk drivers because we have selected
what i o for a network driver and a data
bus
remember okay this bus is not sata this
bus is
so let's start off so i'm going to
minimize
close all of this on my system because
i have a very light system i want to
make it as lighter as possible
very weak system i should say not a
light system okay so click on begin
installation now
uh it will take some time to allocate
the disk space
and it will create the domain and yes it
will connect to graphical console for
guest
and we will start okay so it says press
any key to boot from cd or dvd and
we have pressed it and now i'm gonna
walk you through the steps but i'm
through the magic of video editing i'm
gonna cut down on the time
but remember it will please be patient
it will take at least 40 minutes i don't
know it took me
uh it took me around 45 to 50 minutes i
assume you
it will take you 40 minutes so please
bear with
the installation and don't think it's
going to go as fast as i've shown you on
the video so this is the first step
looks familiar if you have installed
windows 10 so click on next
uh language you you click on install now
and then setup is starting the some
steps are very familiar but some steps
uh they just have a new ui i mean
uh so i'm just gonna walk you through
the entire experience this is like the
full walkthrough
of what will happen when you install
windows 11 on qmu so
uh don't i don't have a product key
click on that no worries
our installation will go down fine in
this screen select windows 11 pro
should be good enough to test and
click on next and it will hopefully
start the installation okay you have to
read the agreement very carefully and
accept all things that microsoft says
click on custom install and see we don't
have any disks
because what i o drivers are not total
so we have to select
word word load driver and just click on
ok
and this will load up all the drivers
from the word io iso file remember
and since we are installing windows 11
which is a
cousin of windows 10 so select windows
10 and click on next
so after the drivers have been loaded
hopefully
we will be seeing the 25 gigs disk that
we allocated
why now this driver will be able to
write and read to the disk
virtual disk that we have selected great
it has detected so
just blindly hit click on next not
linearly i mean click on next
all right so this will start up the
normal windows installation
and we are going to watch the entire
process so it will it will restart
and it will restart twice so you don't
have to click on restart now you can
click on restart and i was
i didn't click on windows it restart now
so it doesn't matter okay so it's
restarts
and it will the the installation will
continue
i know for some guys this part is going
to be boring so if please fast forward
to
the latest section of the video where i
show how to configure the network
drivers
and the display drivers other otherwise
other users
uh i just want to walk you through the
entire process the entire experience
so hang on with me i mentioned this is
not gonna take too long
and you see this is the boot manager and
we have selected efi so there was efi
there it says just a moment
and yes it was not just a moment it took
a long time okay again
i'm skipping i am showing all the
important bits
yeah you see windows 11
and windows has logo has come up
and yes is this the right country or
region
okay united states i'm i'm there yeah
just click on next i'm not the united
states so
it's okay so next step it loads is this
the right input keyboard okay usb port
is defined and click on next
you want a second keyboard uh no i don't
want skip
on skip let's see what comes up next
and oh it wants my wi-fi do we have
wi-fi
no we will not have internet because
anyways this is a vm and we don't have
any site don't have internet
click on that continue with limited
setup
okay microsoft we are continuing with
limited setup don't worry who's going to
use the device please enter your name
and i my name is as you all know is
hikmate usad
so hikmatio start is going to use this
machine create a super miracle password
abcdef
again abcdef super memorable and easy
please add security questions
and after that we will be presented with
this screen
where it says choose privacy settings
for your device
yeah microsoft i know you guys are
tracking me anyway even on this machine
i'm not gonna select
anything so all no no no no no no no no
include optional
i mean this is just the basic setup i
mean if you guys want me to do
like a trim down setup or to make
windows 11 fast
i mean um if a majority of my viewers
say
ask me to you know make a windows 11
video where it's like super fast with no
no tracking and all i'll make it but if
not then this is video okay so it says
hi
and getting things ready for you i know
microsoft you
always get things ready for me with your
updates and i am trying
after each update so i hope this is the
windows 11 has had this might take a few
minutes please keep your
pc on and plugged in good things coming
your way
ah i don't know how where they picked
this slogan
almost there and
yes we are inside see we are in windows
11 congratulations guys
just we are with windows 11
great great great great great almost
almost so we have to fix a couple of
things i'm not going to do a what are
the new things video
you can find on internet man okay and
explorer man they don't have tabs still
i mean microsoft come on guys you should
listen to your users
okay anyways i'm going to fix it the
network and stuff
so come to your vert i o cd and select
the
x 86 or the 64-bit oh i have to check
right the installation
whether it picked up 64-bit or 86-bit so
right-click on
this pc go to properties and see
let's check whether we have a 64-bit
machine or 86-bit
30-bit machine we have a 64-bit machines
great so we are going to pick the 64-bit
version of the driver
so double click on it and install it
what this will do
since we already have the disk drivers
installed this will install the
network drivers and we will be having
internet
and trust me guys i mean i'm surprised
okay so
i'm just showing you if you go to device
manager we see that there are some
devices
that this machine does not recognize and
what io
drivers are going to fix all of them
yes all of them and then we need to
improve on the display drivers okay so
ethernet controller pci you see
we don't have internet so we'll fix it
so close it
click on the next what i o wind driver
installer
click on next let's read and accept the
license agreement
and select all of these guys i mean yeah
select all of these you're going to need
all of them
trust me and click on next and click on
install and it's installing okay uac
prompt click on yes and then if it was
obs
i wouldn't be getting that usc thing
right okay okay so what are you balloon
driver click on is
always trust software from red hat yeah
that artist okay
fine okay no problem and we have
finished the word i o in driver
installation
cool okay that means we have fixed
some of the displays if now if you go to
the display settings
to see what we can do about the display
uh
this doesn't look good to me so if we
right click as of now
after installing the word i o network
drivers we see the display resolution is
locked at
800 by 600 so we can't do anything about
it
to do something about it what we are
going to do is
if i maximize and do is fix full screen
and you get this display
this is horrible not acceptable so if
i'm gonna fix it
guys okay so if if we come to device
manager
remember we installed vert i o drivers
right so see all the yellow things are
gone but we still have microsoft basic
display adapter and which is what we're
going to fix now
so open up our below it microsoft edge
browser and and trust me guys it's a
good browser here i mean
good good it's it's good and let's
search for spice
download so click on
and hit enter okay or do what and come
to this link there it say download spice
i'm going to close the other tab
you see guys we have internet okay you
see we have internet see after
installing the vert i o drivers and see
how fast the internet is so come down
and come to the windows binaries part
where you say windows guest tools and
select on spice guest tools
and wait for it to download see how fast
the download went
okay this wasn't sped up guys i mean
this is all in real time
i did not speed this up so now this is
done so
let's me close the browser and open up
this this explorer to show this i have
downloaded it just right now
in front of you click on download spice
get tools latest
and double click it or hit enter after
clicking it once
and uac prompt click on yes and it will
start the installation of spice against
tool okay let me close the
bra you and click on agree
next and then click on installing
okay it's installing a lot of drivers
were
via your server driver what is your
driver what io serial driver wow okay
wire server driver okay okay executing
and then pretty much okay again
you have command prompt where it is
going to do something all right
okay now see it has already resized okay
we already have a better display guys
see
why we are we already have better
display i mean pretty cool
pretty cool right and once this is done
we will be having
best display so right off the bat just
click on restart after you install the
display drivers so restarting and
we are back please wait we are going to
log
into hikmatio start a b abcde remember
yeah don't keep that password guys i
mean just kidding okay
so now that we are in if now i right
click on
the device manager you will see we have
updated our display adapter from
microsoft basic display adapter
to something and what is that if we
click on there we see red hat q excel
controller remember we had qx
selected in our spice controller okay so
right click display settings
and this time hopefully our display
setting resolutions will be unlocked
see display the resolution is one
through two four seven six eight we
select 1920 by 1080
and it's adjusting do you want to keep
this display setting yes
wow just look at it i mean come on now
i'm going to say view pulse resize no
resize to vm and just say view scale
display always and full screen yes
see will you guys be able to tell this
i'm running out now vm
rather than on an actual hardware if i
showed you this initially
come on guys i mean cool cool very very
cool right so we have a fully functional
windows 11 installation
25 gigs of hard disk space for gives the
ram
and we have like a super i mean
we have a functional windows 11
installation guys i mean see
with the minimal resources we are and
this that is the beauty of qmu
and kvm and that is the beauty of word
io i mean i wanted to show you the most
functional windows 11 installation on a
vm without
using actual hardware so again to show
you how powerful
this thing is and remember guys we don't
have any hardware acceleration we have
not
passed through any hardware accelerator
and i am loading a live stream
on reddit and if you go to youtube
and i want to show you guys how good
this thing is
if we go to youtube and we search for
any film
my favorite is inception and i'll load
up inception
trailer and we'll make it full screen to
see
if we can go full screen and we check
the resolution that youtube thinks
we are on so that i don't we'll see how
how good it is
so if we check on uh let it go full
screen guys okay and we check on setting
c
quality 720p so we can play on 720p
and trust me it's playing smooth i can't
show you inception on this video
so that's it guys thank you so much for
your time
take care see you next time stay safe
[Music]
so
now
[Music]
you