hi welcome to this video in this video
we're going to take a look at how you
can install Windows 11 on KVM step by
step so if you wanted to follow step by
step instruction on my website you can
do that I will put the link in the
description
so before you begin there are some
prerequisites though uh first thing uh
you need to have Windows 11 iOS image
downloaded from the website so I'll put
the link in the description so that you
can go ahead and download that and you
need to have the windows 11 water driver
for KVM so you can also click here to
download that as well finally you need
to have KVM packages installed on your
Linux machine so depending on version of
the Linux machine that you are using you
can just enter the command what I have
shown here and it will let you install
the KVM packages on your machine so I'm
using Ubuntu on my laptop right now so I
just have to copy this entire command
and just paste it on my terminal so let
me copy that and open a terminal and
just right click and paste it and hit
enter
and enter the password for my account
and that's it then you see it's zero
upgraded which means I have already
installed it so I don't need to do
anything so if you don't have it
installed you might have to install it
and then proceed with the next step I
already downloaded the files in the
download directory so for example the
word i o drivers and the windows 11 ISO
file so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
move that files to the KVM directory
which is located in War live word images
as you can see I typed LS and you can
see the files both the files that I have
and I'm gonna move that files to move
the file let me switch the directory CD
home safe downloads
and to move the file you can type MV
for more hyphen T and the destination
which is War live word images and the
two files that I have in this location
so just copy and paste that it will take
some time for to copy these files to the
destination once done you may proceed
with the windows 11 installation so
there are two ways you can install a
Windows 11 on KVM you can use CLI based
or you can use GUI based we are going to
install the windows 11 machine using the
GUI based method okay so for that we
need to use something called
virtualization manager
to open the virtualization manager you
need to type word hyphen manager a
window would appear and which says
virtual machine manager as you can see I
already have an Ubuntu machine in it so
to create a brand new virtual machine
you may click on the create new VM a new
window would pop up so you have
different choices to make you have local
installed media Network install Network
boot import existing disk image so if
you have qcow 2 image you can use the
import existing disk image but in my in
our case it's just a purely a brand new
installation with ISO so you can choose
the first option which is local install
media ISO image or CD-ROM and click on
forward now you need to choose ISO or
CD-ROM for the installation media we
already have it in our location so you
may click on browse and as you can see
by default it took you to the war live
word images directory so you just have
to choose the windows 11 image from
there by default it would automatically
pick up the windows 10 as a operating
system however if you like you can
uncheck the option and manually select
the operating system but at the time of
this recording Windows 11 is not there
in the list better you keep the Windows
10 itself
and click on forward
and you need to configure memory and CPU
four gigs would be fine and two CPUs
should be fine as well but I'm gonna
give maybe eight gigs of RAM and the CPU
I'm gonna give for as you can see I have
12 CPUs so I can give four and you can
also install the windows 11 without any
issues with just two CPUs click on
forward and I'm going to create a
virtual hard disk for the windows 11
machine right so this I'm Gonna Keep it
like 40 gigs that is enough for me if
you have more storage you may increase
it depending on your need and once you
have done that you may click on forward
so here I need to name the VM it has
picked up the windows 10 as a VM name so
I'm gonna change it to Windows 11.
and after that I have to click the
option which says customize
configuration before install and if you
expand the network selection you can see
by default it has picked up Nat which is
good for us and click on finish
as we have chosen customized
configuration before install we got a
window where you can customize a lot of
the configuration that we're gonna use
for the operating system so the first
things first overview we're gonna enable
secure boot here in my previous video I
have shown you how you can enable a
secure Boot and TPM on KVM so you need
to do that first which is already
mentioned in my blog article so you may
follow that and come back here and
continue with this change the chipset to
i44tfx
and the last option in the list and
click on apply and you need to add the
TPM so click on ADD hardware and in the
add new virtual Hardware window choose
DPM in that model choose tis
and click on finish and you can see the
TPM version 2.0 has been added next we
are going to configure the CPU even
though we have allocated for CPU the
Windows machine is not gonna recognize
that so select the CPU under topology
check the option which says manually set
CPU topology so in that sockets change
to one and course 2 threads 2 and in the
current allocation change back to 4 and
click on apply
there is nothing you have to do on the
memory
click on boot options and enable the
CD-ROM which is the windows 11 ISO
and just keep it like that so the first
primary boot device would be the hardest
the world's largest we created and the
second would be Siri ROM so what would
happen is when you boot for the first
time it will try to boot from the hard
disk and since there is no files in it
it will Skip and move to the windows 11
ISO CD-ROM so it will boot from it
install it on the hard disk and once you
reboot the machine then it will boot
from the hard disk because we already
moved the files from the CD-ROM to the
hard disk you keep the settings like
this and click on apply next uh the
virtual hard disk that we created we
need to change that from SATA to word IO
click on apply and we already added the
windows 11 ISO image so we also need to
add another ISO image which is a vertio
KVM driver so to do that click on ADD
hardware and in that choose storage and
click on manage and then this time
choose whether your driver under device
type change that to Siri ROM device and
click on finish when we begin the
installation we have chosen the network
interface as Nat which is good but you
need to change that from device model to
word IO in order for it to work properly
and click on apply next you need to also
add a VNC driver click on ADD R Hardware
and click on Graphics from there type
choose VNC server and click on finish
and you may click on begin installation
so press any key to boot from it so make
sure you press any key so it will boot
from the CD
choose the language of your choice time
keyboard and then click on next and then
install now
the setup would now load
um since I don't have a product key I
can choose I don't have a product key at
the moment and also if you have product
key it is not gonna work because there
is no internet connectivity for the host
which we'll have to fix it at the end of
the installation so for now just choose
I don't have a product key so you will
be getting the versions of Windows that
you're gonna install so I'm gonna choose
Windows 11 Pro and click on next accept
the license agreement and then click on
next
which type of installation do you want
choose custom install Windows only
so where is the virtual hard disk we
don't see any right that's because
there's no driver for it to detect we're
gonna click on load driver and click on
OK because we attach the word or your
driver as a CD ROM it will detect that
so choose Windows 11 from it and then
click on next after few seconds you will
see the virtual hard disk on the
installation screens
so as you can see there's a drive zero
an allocated space so choose that and
then click on next
and the installation just now begin and
you can see the copying file started now
so this process would take some time so
you need to have some patience let me
fast forward this
during the installation it is expected
that the windows will you know reboot
couple of times so just wait for it to
come back up
just a moment
the windows logo just appeared and in
this choose the line you know the
country or region that you would like
keyboard language of your choice
I don't want to add any extra keyboard
and I'm gonna choose I don't have an
internet connection
and I'm gonna continue with the limited
setup if you are using latest version of
Windows 11 ISO image you most likely
won't get I don't have internet option
so what will you do for example this is
my another installation setup with the
latest Windows 11 ISO image in it at the
moment I do not see any option that says
I don't have internet connection and
many users will stuck here and here is a
workaround for that while you are on the
screen press shift F10 you might have to
use function key as well for it to work
you'll get a command prompt here you
need to enter the command o o b e
backslash bypass nro and hit enter the
system would now reboot and after it's
come back up you will have to start over
again with the windows 11 initial setup
wizard eventually on the let's connect
you to the network screen you now get an
option that says I don't have internet
click on that and continue with the
limited setup the one more benefit of
not having the internet connectivity is
that you can create your local account
so continue with the limited setup and
then it will ask you to set up the
username and password and things like
that so under the you know username that
you're going to use
and then next and come come from the
password and then next it will ask you
three security questions so you may
answer them and then click on next uh so
in the privacy settings you choose
whatever you like almost there
this is the desktop and you don't see
some of the logos because we don't have
internet connectivity yet on the machine
so we're gonna fix that right now
if I click on display settings
I don't see any options to add just
screen size because there is no driver
for it which we're gonna fix it right
now so click on the start menu and go to
computer management a window would
appear and choose device manager and as
you can see there are some drivers which
is not present on the operating systems
so first uh we are going to fix a
network adapter ethernet controller
under other devices so right click on
the ethernet controller click on update
driver and browse my computer for
drivers
and attach some CD drive that we have
added with the word IO
and it will search for the drivers for
the ethernet adapter as you can see it
has picked up the red advert IO ethernet
adapter so which which is good so after
that click on close
and then let's head on to PCI device so
right click on that and do the same
procedure like what we did for the
network adapter and it will also install
the drivers close this
we're gonna do it for the last drivers
as well there's one more thing that we
need to do which is the display adapter
that we need to install or upgrade right
so we already have Microsoft you know
generic adapter so we're going to update
that as well right click on that basic
adapter update it and just like we did
for the other drivers just do it as well
all right and if you go to the display
settings you will see I now have the
options to adjust the display resolution
which is good so I can just keep the
changes
okay which is good you can also see the
internet connection is back online next
thing what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go
to open up the edge since I'm opening
the edge for the first time I'm getting
some welcome screen from the Microsoft
the main important part is to understand
whether I can access the internet
download right so
I can open my website just fine and
that's it we have just installed the
windows 11 on KVM and you can open the
RDP and start using it thanks for
watching and I'll see you guys on the
next one